在2018年年底
At the end of 2018,
博卡奇卡小镇以为当地居民分享了一张太空叉新发射场的一个巨型物体照片
a local resident of Boca Chica shared an image of a new structure at the SpaceX site.
许多人认为这只是一个大水塔而已
Most people assumed that this was nothing more than a new water tower.
但经过各路神仙分析过后
But after rounds of speculation,
太空叉出来澄清这是刚开始建造的Starship
SpaceX revealed that this structure was actually the beginnings of Starship.
在当时 太空叉在博卡奇卡小镇的活动还没什么动静
At the time, SpaceX's activity down in Boca Chica was extremely quiet.
他们所有家当就是工地立起来的一个小棚子
Their entire facility consisted of a small tent at the build site
发射场还有一堆烂泥巴
and a pile of dirt at the launch site.
工人没几个
There were only a handful of workers
谁也不知道博卡奇卡小镇对于Starship的研发有多重要
and no one really knew how important Boca Chica would be for Starship's development.
毕竟多数人都以为Starship会在加州建造
After all, most people were expecting Starship to be manufactured in California,
因为太空叉多数员工都在那边上班、生活
where most of the SpaceX engineers lived and worked.
那为什么太空叉会选择博卡奇卡小镇作为Starship项目的基地呢？
So why did SpaceX choose Boca Chica as the base for their Starship project?
虽然博卡奇卡小镇基础设施差 还缺乏熟练劳动力
Despite the lack of basic infrastructure or a skilled workforce,
但那边土地便宜 很多地方还未开发的无人区
Boca Chica offered an abundance of cheap land in an area that was mostly uninhabited.
这点对太空叉来说很重要
This was extremely important for SpaceX
因为这种尺度的火箭测试起来 对于周围的居民都有很大的风险
since testing rockets on this scale would pose quite a risk to any nearby residents.
但博卡奇卡小镇并不是完全没人住
But Boca Chica wasn't completely uninhabited.
紧挨着工地的就是一个村庄主体 由35座房屋组成
Right next to the build site was the main village, which consisted of 35 houses.
简直是养老天堂度假胜地 但太空叉说不行 得改
This spot was a dream location for retirees and vacationers, but SpaceX was about to change that.
为了使该地区完全无人 太空叉开始了收购整个小镇的过程
In order to make the area completely uninhabited, SpaceX began the process of buying out the entire town.
他们给居民写信 提出了三倍市场价的收购价
And sent letters to residents, offering to buy their homes at three times the market value.
在接下来几年 太空叉买下了越来越多的土地 雇佣了上百名工人
Over the next couple of years, SpaceX purchased more and more land and hired hundreds of workers
让他们7×24小时换班
to begin a 24/7 work cycle.
时至今日 博卡奇卡的太空叉设施仍在继续发展
To this day, the SpaceX facility in Boca Chica continues to grow,
有新的计划来扩大发射场 并增加更多的发射架和着陆场
with new plans to expand the launch site and add on additional launch mounts and landing pads.
但这里的目标并不仅仅是建一个超大的Starship工厂
But the goal here isn't just to create an enormous Starship factory.
太空叉想建一座城市 名字叫“星际基地”
SpaceX wants to build an entire city, and call it 'Starbase'.
虽然博卡奇卡是一个发射和降落火箭的好地方
Although Boca Chica is a great place for launching and landing rockets,
但当地有水平的航天工程师并不多
it isn't exactly well known for its skilled aerospace engineers.
目前 博卡奇卡发射场当地的一些工人
Right now, the Boca Chica site consists of some local workers
都是太空叉从加州派过去的
and SpaceX employees that fly in from California.
许多工人都是签了六个月的合约
Many of these workers are on 6 month contracts
每半年往返于太空叉在加州霍桑和得州麦格雷戈的基地
and shift in and out from SpaceX's main facilities in Hawthorne and McGregor, Texas.
太空叉要在这些员工身上花费大量的差旅费
For all of these employees,
SpaceX has to spend an enormous amount of money on travel and accommodation costs.
他们在加州的总部汇集了世界上最聪明的头脑
For their headquarters in California, they have the world's brightest minds at their doorstep.
在过去二十年间
Over the last two decades,
太空叉建立起了一支相当牛逼的技术与工程团队
this has allowed SpaceX to build the most incredible team of engineers and technicians.
对于其中很多年轻的工程师来说 能在太空叉工作简直是一种福报
For many young engineers, working at SpaceX is the dream job.
但为了让更多的人才能够来到博卡奇卡小镇
But in order to attract the brightest minds to Boca Chica,
太空叉需要让这个地方更能吸引优秀人才
SpaceX needs to make the area much more appealing.
为了让星际基地更适宜居住
In order for Starbase to be a nice place to live,
城市里需要有一般城市都该有的基础设施
the city needs to have all of the amenities you would typically find in a city.
需要让人感觉宾至如归
It needs to be a warm and homely place
这样技术工人才能放心拖家带口搬来这里定居
so that the families of the workers will also be happy to move there.
去年 太空叉开始在工地附近建餐厅和夏威夷风情酒吧
Last year, SpaceX started building a restaurant and a tiki bar right next to the build site
工人可以在一天繁忙的工作后来这里休息
where employees can relax after a long day of work.
这些项目中不少都来自去年他们开设的新工种的指示——度假区开发经理
Many of these projects fall under the guidance of a new job which opened up last year,
a Resort Development Manager.
这项工作可能涉及为他们未来的太空港设计和设施规划
This job will likely involve designing and planning facilities for their future spaceport.
这将是一个为期待首次太空飞行的高薪客户提供服务的迷人度假胜地
This will be a glamorous resort
for the high paying customers that they expect to have for their first flights into space.
但实际上 太空旅游只是星际基地的一小部分内容
But realistically, space tourism is only a small part of what Starbase is about.
招不来工人 说啥都没用
Unless they can attract the workers, none of this will happen.
星际基地的一个更独特的亮点将是放置在高台顶部的未来主义酒吧
One of the more unique features of Starbase
will be the futuristic bar placed at the top of the high bay.
这座80米高的建筑有一个巨型起重机
This 80 meter tall building has a large gantry crane
用来总装Starship的两级
which is used to stack large sections of Starship.
酒吧将被放置在这个区域的正上方
The bar will be placed right above this area,
有玻璃窗 可以360度俯瞰星际基地
with glass windows and a 360 degree view looking out over Starbase.
太空叉计划将这个酒吧向公众开放
SpaceX plans to open this bar up to the public.
但就目前而言 这些区域只对太空叉员工开放
But for now, these areas are only open to SpaceX employees.
但是大多数员工现在实际上住在哪里呢？
But where do most of these employees actually live?
在距离高台仅200米的地方有一个小营地 停着30多辆露营车
Just 200 meters away from the high bay is a small campsite, home to over 30 Airstream trailers.
这些复古风格的拖车有车载厨房和最多可容纳8人的睡眠空间
These retro styled trailers have onboard kitchens and sleeping spaces for up to 8 people.
虽然看起来空间利用率挺高
Although it seems like an efficient use of space,
但每个拖车价值5到10万元不等
each trailer can cost between $50,000 and $100,000.
这钱已经可以在博卡奇卡买下一整套房产了
For that amount of money, you could get an entire property in the Boca Chica village.
而这也正是太空叉所做的事
But that's exactly what SpaceX have done.
在收购镇里多数的房屋后
After buying out most of the remaining villagers,
太空叉的员工已经搬进来开始装修 寻找家的感觉了
SpaceX employees moved into these homes and started renovating them until they felt more like home.
预计仅在未来2年内 星际基地的人口将增长几千人
It's expected that the population of Starbase will grow by several thousand in just the next 2 years,
因此该地区将需要建造更多的房屋
so many more homes will need to be built in the area.
所以很明显 星际基地将不仅仅是一个火箭工厂或太空游客的度假村
So it's clear that Starbase will be more than just a rocket factory or a resort for space tourists.
而星际基地究竟会有多大？
But how big will Starbase actually be
太空叉需要做什么才能真正开始建造一个城市？
and what do SpaceX need to do in order to start a city?
根据马一龙所说 星际基地会覆盖比博卡奇卡更广的区域
According to Elon Musk, Starbase will cover a much wider area than Boca Chica.
很可能博卡奇卡小镇与和它最近的城市布朗斯维尔之间的闲置土地
It's likely that the unused land between Boca Chica and the nearest city of Brownsville
也会成为星际基地的一部分
will become part of Stabase.
目前 博卡奇卡小镇属于未立案的村庄
Right now, Boca Chica is known as an unincorporated village.
这基本上意味着没有公司来提供执法、消防部门和建筑维护等服务
This basically means that no corporation is there to provide services like law enforcement,
fire departments and building maintenance.
要想给一个地区立案
In order for an area to become incorporated,
就得先向地区政府提交申请
a petition has to be started with the local county
各种细节部分都要经过当地居民的同意
and the details need to be approved by the local residents.
在本例中 大多数居民现在都是太空叉的自己人
In this instance, the majority of the residents are now SpaceX employees,
手续应该会简单不少
which might make this process a little bit easier.
但是申请立案本来就是一个很复杂的事情 对于这样的小镇来说更是罕见
But seeking incorporation is a complex process and one that is especially rare for this county,
而太空叉星际基地的宏伟计划却早已影响到博卡奇卡小镇以外的地区
but SpaceX's grand plans for Starbase have affected areas outside of the Boca Chica village.
附近的布朗斯维尔市——有很多员工来自那里
The nearby city of Brownsville - where many employees come from -
——在过去几年里发生了巨大的变化
has seen a drastic change in just the last couple of years.
太空叉一进城
As soon as SpaceX rolled into town,
得州政府就给布朗斯维尔提供了上百万美元的拨款
the state of Texas gave Brownsville millions of dollars in public relief,
用于改善城市市容
with the aim to improve the appearance of the city.
马一龙自己也给布朗斯维尔地区捐了三千万美元
Elon Musk himself has donated over $30 million to the Brownsville area.
如今 星际基地计划一经公开
Now that the plans for Starbase are out in the open,
大量布朗斯维尔的居民就察觉到了机遇 开始给新产业注资
many residents of Brownsville are sensing the opportunities and investing in new businesses.
但很多本地人并不这样认为
But for many of the locals, they don't see it that way.
布朗斯维尔是全美国最贫穷的城市之一
Brownsville is one of the poorest cities in the country,
许多百姓还没有脱贫摘帽
with many residents living in poverty.
尽管许多拥有餐馆、商店和酒店等业务的当地人会因太空叉的到来而受益
Although many locals with businesses such as restaurants, shops and hotels
stand to benefit from SpaceX's arrival,
但随着经济的增长和税收的增加 那些没有工作的人将会受到严重影响
those without businesses will suffer as the economy grows and taxes start to increase.
为此 许多本地人完全反对星际基地的想法
For this reason, many of the locals are completely against the idea of Starbase.
但无论如何 博卡奇卡的高质量发展是令全美人民惊叹的
But either way, the incredible developments down in Boca Chica are mesmerizing to watch.
太空叉无疑对星际基地及其周边地区有着宏伟的规划
It's no doubt that SpaceX has extremely grand plans for Starbase and the surrounding areas.
未来十年 我们应该看到美国尚在贫困线以下的地区之一
Over the next decade, we should see one of the poorest parts of the country
一转成为一个繁荣的、载着人类前往火星梦想的工业城市
turn into a thriving industrial city with the hopes of becoming the gateway to Mars.
这样的脱贫攻坚战需要每一个人漫长的奋斗
It will be a long and hard journey for everyone involved.
如果参考人类航天史的话
But if the history of spaceflight is anything to go by,
那星际基地带来的大量优势无疑会为人类提供更大的舞台
humanity will flourish with the untold advancements that Starbase will bring.
如果想支持Primal Space频道 欢迎去Patreon赞助
If you'd like to support Primal Space even more, consider becoming a Patron,
可以加入片尾赞助列表 还能加Discord群
where you can give your input on each video and join our exclusive Discord server.
感谢观看 我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.